vhcc.edu 2006-05-19

# Virginia Highlands Community College Privacy Statement

**Virginia Highlands Community College Privacy Statement. **

Virginia Highlands Community College takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy.

**NOTICE:[Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html) for important information about safe surfing from the Federal Trade Commission.**

_“It is the policy of the Commonwealth of Virginia that personal information about citizens will be collected only to the extent necessary to provide the service or benefit desired; that only appropriate information will be collected; that the citizen shall understand the reason the information is collected and be able to examine their personal record which is maintained by a public body.” _

**What this Privacy Policy Covers**

  * This Privacy Policy covers VHCC’s treatment of personally identifiable information that VHCC collects when you are on the VHCC site, and when you use VHCC’s on-line services. 
  * This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that VHCC does not own or control, or to people that VHCC does not employ or manage. 

**Information Collection and Use **

  * VHCC collects personally identifiable information when you register for certain VHCC web services. VHCC may also receive personally identifiable information from our business partners. 
  * When you apply for an on-line service with VHCC, we ask for your name, email address, birth date, gender, phone, zip code, occupation, curriculum, industry, and comments. 
  * VHCC may also automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, VHCC cookie information and the page you requested. 
  * VHCC uses information for two general purposes: 1) to fulfill your requests for certain services, and 2) to contact you with information and new services. 
  * If you find errors in the information that you submitted to VHCC through the website or want to examine your information, you should contact the webmaster by email at [webmaster@vhcc.edu](mailto:webmaster@vhcc.edu).  You may also contact the Webmaster by writing to: Webmaster, Virginia Highlands Community College, P.O. Box 828, Abingdon, Virginia, 24212.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

  * VHCC will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to anyone. 
  * VHCC will send personally identifiable information about you to other companies or people when: 
    * We have your consent to share the information; 
    * We need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; 
    * We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of VHCC to provide a product or service to you. (Unless we tell you differently, these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to assist us.); 
    * We respond to subpoenas, court orders and legal processes. ** **

·         VHCC does not currently use cookies, but may set and access VHCC cookies on your computer.

_A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, which is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. _

Each web site can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's  preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. 

## Choices about Cookies

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or  notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.)

  * In certain areas VHCC uses standard e-mail or databases to store data transmissions.

  * VHCC may edit this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes we will notify you by posting a prominent announcement on our pages.
